A Guide to the Washington Irving Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6256-a
Washington Irving Collection 1789-1869
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6256-a
312 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
This collection bears no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Deposit 1960 Mar 19
Item Listing
- MANUSCRIPTS
  - Abbotsford, 1835 Apr 6; AMsS, 1 p. (portion)
  - Address by Washington Irving upon his return from Europe, [1832]; AMs, 8 p. (in slipcase)
  - " Alonzo the Catholic, " [an early draft later rewritten for Spanish Papers ], n. d.; AMs, 26 p.
  - " Alonzo the Chaste, " [an early draft later rewritten for Spanish Papers ], n. d.; AMS, 25 p.
  - Astoria, [1836]; AMs, 123 p. (in slipcase)
  - Bonneville, portion incl. portion of " Rocky Mountains ", [1837]; AMS, 2 p.
  - Bracebridge Hall: "The Hall" (portion), n. d.; AMs, 1 p.
  - Bracebridege Hall: "The Library", n. d.; AMs, 5 p.
  - Bracebridge Hall: "Love Charms", n. d.; AMS, 8 p.
  - Bracebridge Hall: "The Student of Salamanca", n. d.; AMs, 14 p. (portion)
  - Bracebridege Hall: "The Student of Salamanca", n. d.; AMs, 10 p. (portion)
  - Bracebridege Hall: "Fortune Telling", n. d.; AMs, 8 p. (portion)
  - Bracebridge Hall, n. d.; AMs, 7 p. portion (in slipcase)
  - [" Chronicle of the Ommiades "], n. d.; AMs, 1 p. (portion)
  - Preface to Life and Voyages of Columbus, 1827; AMsS, 4 p.
  - Life and Voyages of Columbus, [1850]; Pntd, 4 vols.
    1828 printed edition, as prepared for the publisher of the 1850 edition, with additions and corrections in hand of Washington Irving and a secretary, in 4 bound volumes.
  - Life and Voyages of Columbus, Pntd, 3 vols
    printed edition with autograph corrections and additions for a new addition, in 3 slipcases
  - The History of the Life and Voyages of Christopher Columbus, Book 6, Chapter 6 (pp. 564-571 of first edition), AMS, 8 p.
  - Life and Voyages of Columbus (portion: pp. 102-103 of Vol. III of the 1828 G & C Cavill edition), AMs, 1 p.
  - Life and Voyages of Columbus, AMs, 2 p. (portion)
  - The Conquest of Granada, n. d.; Pntd, 44 ptnd, 16 Ms in slipcase
    printed pages with autograph corrections and additions for a new edition
  - Voyages and Discoveries of the Companions of Columbus, 24 of 36 chapters, in 2 bound volumes, AMs, 465 p. (portion)
  - " A Contented Man, " signed " Geoffrey Crayon", n. d.; AMsS, 10 p. (portion)
  - " Broek, " signed " Geoffrey Crayon", [1841]; AMsS, 2 p. (portion)
  - " The Charming Letorieres, " signed "G.C.", [1840]; AMsS, 10 p.
  - " English and French Character, " signed " Geoffrey Crayon", [1825]; AMsS, 8 p. in bound volume
    w/ note to the publisher, an engraving of Washington Irving, and the following two items laid in.
  - Leaf beginning "...a song from a group of sailors...", n. d.; AMs, 1 p. (fragment)
  - Essay beginning "I trust I shall not be deemed irreverent...", n. d.; AMs, 1 p.
  - " Guests from Gibbet Island ", [1839 Oct]; AMs, 8 p. (portion)
  - [" Irving's Power of Idealization "] by Oliver Wendell Holmes, AMsS, 7 p.
  - Knickerbocker's History of New York, n. d.; AMs, 2 p. (portion)
  - Knickerbocker's History of New York, n. d.; Pntd, 2 p.
    printed fragment w/ autograph corrections
  - Life of Mahomet, early draft of a portion of Chapter I, n. d.; AMs, 16 p.
  - " Mathews Not at Home ", n. d.; AMs, 4 p.
  - " Milton's Account of His Motives for Writing his Paradise Lost ", n. d.; AMs, 6 p.
  - Newstead Abbey, notes. Originally included were transcripts of the following letters: 1825 Jun 22, Sophia Hyatt to [ Thomas Wildman]; 1825 Jul 4, Sophia Hyatt to [Wildman]; 1825 Sep 20, Sophia Hyatt to [ Louisa Wildman]; n.y. Jul 13, Sophia Hyatt to [Wildman], n. d.; AMs, 104 p.
  - Notebook of quotation from English authors, [1823]; AMs, 42 p. bound, (in slipcase)
    w/ engraving of Washington Irving
  - Notebook or a journal, [1817]; AMs, 2 p. (portion)
  - Note book of Peter Irving, re: Arthurian Legends, AMs, 39 p. in slipcase
  - " Paris at the Restoration ", n. d.; AMs, 14 p. (in bound volume)
    w/ engraving of Washington Irving and printed version
  - " Rocky Mountains ". Listed also as Bonneville, [1837]; AMs, 1 p. (portion)
  - Salmagundi, "Cocklost Hall", AMsS, 1 p. (portion)
    signed "Launcelot Langstaff." Originally included ALS, 1812 Dec 16, Washington Irving to D. Longworth
  - The Sketch Book, quotation beginning "With the true poet...", 1815 Jun 28; AMsS, 1 p.
  - "Chronicle of Don Garcia Fernandez" [unpublished], AMs, 19 p. (in slipcase)
  - " Fernan Gonzales ", [1866]; AMs, 108 p. (in slipcase)
  - " Fernando the Saint " portion of early version of Chapter 1, AMs, 3 p.
  - " Fernando the Saint " portion of early version of Chapter 1 (Riverside 402-403), AMs, 1 p.
  - " Fernando the Saint " portion of early version of Chapter 1 (Riverside 401-404), AMs, 7 p.
  - " Fernando the Saint " portion of early version of Chapter 1 [Apparently not used], AMs, 1 p.
  - " Fernando the Saint " ["Battle of Prince Alonzo"] portion of early version of Chapter 6 (Riverside 427-434), AMs, 10 p.
  - " Fernando the Saint " portions of early version of Chapters 7 and 8 (Riverside 435-441), AMs, 18 p.
  - " Fernando the Saint " portions of early version of Chapter 8 w/ portions of Chapters 11 and 12 and notes on verso of a page, AMs, 15 p.
  - " Fernando the Saint " portions of early version of Chapter 9 w/ portions of Chapter 13, AMs, 7 p.
  - " Fernando the Saint " portions of early version of Chapter 10 (Riverside 455), AMs, 4 p.
  - " Fernando the Saint " portions of early version of Chapters 10 and 11 (Riverside 454-457), Ams, 2 p.
  - " Fernando the Saint " portions of early version, AMs, 16 p.
  - " Fernando the Saint " portion of final version of Chapter 17, AMs, 8 p.
  - " Fernando the Saint " Chapter 18, final version, AMs, 19 p.
  - " Fernando the Saint " Chapter 19, final version, AMs, 9 p.
  - " Fernando the Saint " portion of final version of Chapter 20, AMs, 8 p.
    w/note on verso of first leaf, later put into Chapter 21
  - " Fernando the Saint " portion of final version of Chapter 21, AMs, 2 p.
  - " Fernando the Saint ", [1866]; AMs, 97 p. in slipcase
  - " The Legend of Pelayo ", [1866]; AMs, 68 p. in slipcase
  - A legend about a Spanish family feud, [unpublished], [1828]; AMs, 36 p. portion (in slipcase)
  - " A Spanish Tale ", n. d.; AMs, 2 p. (portion)
  - " Ay Dios de Mi Alma, " poem, 1830 Sep 9; AMsS, 2 p.
  - Poem by John Dowring, 1831 Jul 7, beginning, "O not for me...", AMsS, 1 p.
  - Tales of a Traveller, "A Practical Philosopher", [1828]; AMs, 6 p.
    addressed to H. E. Parker w/ address
  - A Trip Through the West, n. d.; AMs, 8 p. (portion)
  - " The Vindication of Christmas ", AMs, 7 p. (in slipcase)
  - Life of George Washington, notes in notebook, n. d.; AMs, 125 p. (in slipcase)
  - Life of George Washington, notes, n. d.; AMs, 18 p. (in slipcase)
  - Life of George Washington, Chapter 10, n. d.; AMs, 8 p.
    in bound volume with engraving of Lafayette, Washington, Mt. Vernon, and Washington Irving; and facsimiles of ALS, 1852 Dec 27, Irving to George P. Putnam and ALS, 1856 Feb 2, Irving to Joseph Tuttle
  - Life of George Washington, Chapter 15, Volume 5, n. d.; AMs, 22 p.
    w/ facsimile page from this AMs marked "178."
  - Life of George Washington, n. d.; AMs, 2 p. (portion)
  - Life of George Washington, n. d.; AMs, 2 p. (portion)
  - Life of George Washington, n. d.; AMs, 3 p. (portions)
  - Life of George Washington, n. d.; AMs, 2 p. (portion)
    w/notation "Remembrances. Oct. 5, 1778"
  - Life of George Washington, n. d.; AMs, 1 p. (portion)
  - Life of George Washington, n. d.; Proof, 6 p. (portion)
    corrected page proofs w/ 3 AMs add.
  - Wolfert's Roost (portions: p. 314), n. d.; AMs, 1 p.
  - Notes re: Adam and the Fall, probably first copy of MSS in 6256- m, AMs, 1 p.
  - Notes re: Charlotte Lennox and William Shakespeare, AMs, 2 p.
  - Page beginning, "Seeing there was no avoiding...", n. d.; AMs, 1 p.
  - Page beginning, "She opened the door...", n. d.; AMs, 2 p.
  - Page beginning, "What time the persons of these...", n. d.; AMs, 3 p.
- CORRESPONDENCE
  - William Irving [ Washington Irving's father] to D. Fonda, w/ addr, 1789 Jan 4; ALS, 1 p.
  - Herman Knickerbocker to Harmanus Bleecker, w/addr, 1802 Aug 8; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to [ Alvah Beebee], 1804 Aug 24; ALS, 8 p.
  - Washington Irving to [ Alvah Beebee], 1804 Sep 18; ALS, 18 p.
  - Washington Irving to [ Alvah Beebee], 1805 Aug 3; ALS, 8 p.
  - William Irving[ Washington Irving's brother] to William Van Ness, w/addr, 1805 Feb 7; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to William Van Ness, w/ addr, 1811 Feb 20; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to Mrs. [James] Madison, 1811 Mar 10; ALS, 2 p. (portion)
  - William Irving[ Washington Irving's brother] to William Van Ness, w/ addr, 1811 Mar 23; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to D. Longworth, 1812 Dec 16; ALS, 2 p.
    (originally in slipcase with
    Salmagundi
    )
  - John Murray to [ Washington Irving], [1814 Feb]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Henry Lee w/addr, 1815 Jan 11; ALS, 1 p.
  - William Irving[ Washington Irving's brother] to Messrs. Tucker and Lawrie, w/ addr, 1816 Jan 29; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Peter Irving, w/ addr, 1817 Sep 1; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to Peter Irving, w/ addr, 1817 Sep 6; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to Peter Irving, w/ addr, 1817 Sep 20; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to Peter Irving, w/ addr, 1817 Sep 22; ALS, 3 p.
  - T[homas] Campbell to Washington Irving, w/ addr, 1818 May 11; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Joseph Hopkins, w/ addr, 1818 Sep 24; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to Mr. Bartley, w/ addr, 1818 Sep 28; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Henry Brevoort, 1818 Apr 1; ALS, 3 p.
    in re: The Sketch Book, w/ addr
  - Washington Irving to [James] Hillhouse, 1819 May 11; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to John Irving, w/ addr, 1819 May 13; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to Henry Brevoort, w/ addr, 1819 Aug 16; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to G. S. Newton, [ca. 1819]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to [ John Howard] Payne, w/addr, [1821 Jul 9]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to George Jay, w/ addr, [1821 Aug 10]; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to John Howard Payne, w/ addr, 1822 Mar 17; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to [G. S.] Newton, [1822] Jul 5; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to [G. S.] Newton, 1822 Dec 2; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Madame [John] Foster, w/ addr, [1823 May 21]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to W. [Hutchinson], [ca. 1823]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to John Murray, w/ addr, 1825 Jun 1; ALS, 1 p.
  - Sophia Hyatt to [ Thomas Wildman], 1825 Jun 22; ALS, 6 p.
  - Sophia Hyatt to [ Thomas Wildman or Louisa Wildman], 1825 Jul 4; ALS, 5 p.
  - Washington Irving to Emily Foster, 1825 Aug 23; ALS, 5 p.
    w/ printed article, " Washington Irving's Religion," by Stanley Williams, from
    Yale Review
    , Jan 1926, w/ addr
  - Sophia Hyatt to Lousia Wildman, 1825 Sep 20; ALS, 10 p. (transcript)
  - Washington Irving to John Howard Payne, w/ addr, 1826 Feb 25; ALS, 3 p.
  - Peter Irving to Christopher Hughes, (transcript: original in W. L. Clements Library), 1826 Jul 28; ALS, 6 p.
  - Washington Irving to William Macready, w/ addr, 1826 Oct 22; ALS, 2 p.
  - Albert Gallatin to Thomas Aspinwall, re: Washington Irving's Life of Christopher Columbus, 1827 Aug 24; ALS, 1 p.
  - Peter Irving to [ Christopher Hughes], 1827 Oct 14; ALS, 3 p. (transcript)
  - Washington Irving to [ Baring Brothers], 1827 Nov 17; ALS, 1 p. (copy)
  - Washington Irving to Henry Carey, w/ addr, 1828 Aug 31; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to Thomas Aspinwall, w/ addr, 1828 Aug 31; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to Thomas Aspinwall, 1828 Sep 18; ALS, 3 p.
    includes Introduction to
    Conquest of Granada
    , w/ addr
  - Washington Irving to Thomas Aspinwall, w/ addr, 1828 Oct 22; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to [ I. M. Brackenburg], 1829 Apr 11; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to David Wilkie, w/ addr, 1829 May 15; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to unknown, re: novel to be submitted to Murray or Longmans, [1829] Jul 9; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to Henry Van Wert, w/ addr, 1829 Oct 1; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to Byng, [1829] Oct 27; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to [Christopher] Hughes, 1829 Nov 20; ALS, 1 p. (transcript)
  - Washington Irving to [John Howard] Payne, [1829] Dec 7; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to [ John Murray], [1829] Dec 15; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to A[lexander] H[ill] Everett, w/ addr, [ca. 1829]; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to J. K. Teffts, w/ addr, 1830 Mar 13; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to [I. M.] Brackenburg, w/ addr, 1830 May 7; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to [John] Wetherell, 1830 May 13; ALS, 4 p.
    re:
    Companions of Columbus
    and Royal Society Medal, w/ addr
  - Washington Irving to [ James Bandinal], [1830] May 28; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to [Joseph] Payne, [1830] Sep 4; AL, 1 p.
    (in third person)
  - Washington Irving to Maria Hopkins, w/ addr, 1830 Oct 21; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to John [Murray], [ca. 1830]; ALS, 1 p.
    A Year in Spain
  - Washington Irving to unknown, [1830] Jan 4; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to unknown, [1830] Jun 3; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to unknown, [1830] Aug 22; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Mr. Niles, 1831 May 31; AL, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to John Murray, 1831 Jul 27; ALS, 1 p.
    w/ printed drawing of Irving standing, w/ addr
  - Washington Irving to Thomas Aspinwall, w/ addr, 1831 Oct 22; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to Robert Sulivan, w/ addr, 1831 Nov 25; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to R. Montgomery, w/ addr, 1832 Apr 3; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to [Frank] Mills, 1832 Sep 4; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to [Charles] Latrobe, [1832] Nov 16; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to Catherine Paris, w/ addr, 1832 Nov 16; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to Catherine Paris, w/ addr, 1833 Feb 27; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to Mathew Davis, w/ addr, 1835 Feb 4; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to Aaron Vail, w/ addr, 1835 May 22; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Aaron Vail, w/ addr, 1835 Jun 20; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to unknown, 1835 Jun 23; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Thomas Aspinwall, w/ addr, 1835 Jul 15; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to [Thomas] Spring Rice, w/ addr, 1836 Mar 21; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Gouverneur Kemble, w/ addr, 1837 Mar 17; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to the Right Rev. William Clancy, 1837 Aug 2; ALS, 1 p.
    with transcript of ALS, 1 p., 1837 Aug 2, Washington Irving to Thomas Wildman
  - Washington Irving to S. Ward, Jr., w/ addr, 1837 Sep 20; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to Catherine Paris, w/ addr, 1838 Mar 22; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to George Houghton, w/ addr, 1838 Jun 24; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to William H[enry] Seward, 1838 Sep 22; ALS, 2 p.
    w/ addr, w/ newspaper clipping re: Washington Irving; and AMsS quotation, 1882 Dec 26, by John Townsend Trowbridge, pasted on back
  - Washington Irving to David Hoffman, w/ addr, 1839 Aug 22; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to John Littel, 1839 Oct 13; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Eliza[beth] Leslie, w/ addr, 1839 Dec 20; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to William H[ickling] Prescott, w/ addr, 1840 Jan 21; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to unknown, 1840 May 20; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Charles Bristed, w/ addr, 1840 Sep 28; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Aaron Vail, w/ addr, 1841 May 11; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Lucius Baldwin, 1842 Feb 22; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Daniel Webster, 1842 Apr 2; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to Richard Bently, w/ addr, 1842 Apr 4; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to George Ticknor, 1842 Apr 6; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to G[eorge] Gibson, 1842 May 18; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Eliza Romeyn, w/ addr, 1842 Aug 16; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to William Freeman, 1842 Aug 27; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Edward Everett, 1842 Oct 7; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to Irving Paris, w/ addr, 1843 Jan 10; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to [ Catherine Paris], 1843 Jan 12; ALS, 19 p.
  - Washington Irving to [ Catherine Paris], 1843 Aug 10; ALS, 14 p.
  - Washington Irving to [ Aaron Vail], 1843 Sep 20; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to [Catherine] Paris, 1843 Oct 12; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to [Catherine] Paris, w/ addr, 1843 Dec 10; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to [Catherine] Paris, w/ addr, 1844 Jan 20; ALS, 7 p.
  - Washington Irving to unknown, 1844 Mar 15; ALS, 2 p. (fragment)
  - Washington Irving to [an aspiring author], 1844 Jul 27; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to Catherine Paris, w/ addr, 1844 Sep 15; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to William H[ickling] Prescott, 1844 Oct 15; ALS, 4 p.
    Conquest of Mexico
  - Pierre Irving to A. Carrington, 1845 Jun 2; ALS, 2 p.
    w/ addr, enclosing copy of ALS, 1845 May 31, Commissioner of Pensions to Washington Irving
  - Pierre Irving to A. Carrington, w/ addr, 1845 Jun 19; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to Irving [Paris], 1845 Aug 7; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to [ Benjamin Poore], 1845 Dec 20; ALS, 2 p.
    w/ ALS, 1895 Dec 28, Barclay Dunham to Mrs. Borland, re: Irving letter
  - Washington Irving to [ Catherine Paris], 1846 Feb 3; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Georgiana Bennett, 1846 Feb 10; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to [ Catherine Paris], 1846 Mar 16; ALS, 8 p.
  - Washington Irving to Don Xavier Isturiz, [1846 Jul 17]; ALS, 12 p.
    (draft) w/ photostat of final revision of the letter
  - Pierre Irving to [W. S.] Wilcox, 1846 Jul 21; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to [ Catherine Paris], 1847 Sep 9; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to I. Prince, 1848 Apr 24; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to T. L. [Dunnall], 1848 Aug 5; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to [Charles] Leslie, w/ addr, 1848 Oct 19; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to Thomas Picton, 1849 Jun 10; ALS, 2 p.
    w/ typed copy of an article from the
    New York Evening Post
    , 1857 Jul 14, re: authors of
  - Washington Irving to Victor, 1850 Oct 9; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to unknown, 1950 Dec 18; ALS, 8 p.
  - Washington Irving to unknown, 1851 Mar 31; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to George P[almer] Putnam, 1851 May 15; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to Sir Robert Harry Inglis, 1851 Nov 20; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to [Gouverneur] Kemble with a photograph of Irving, 1852 Feb 5; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to Mr. Ogden, 1852 Nov 23; ALS, 1 p.
    re: "Dedications"
  - Washington Irving to Alfred Clarke, 1852 Dec 21; ALS, 1 p. w/ env
  - Washington Irving to unknown, 1852 Dec 27; ALS, 1 p.
    re: Sir Walter Scott autograph
  - Washington Irving to George P[almer] Putnam, 1852 Dec 27; ALS, 3 p.
    (facsimile) in bound volume w/ Chapter 10 of
    Life of George Washington
  - Washington Irving to unknown, [ca. 1852]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Industrial Association of New York, 1853 Jan 10; ALS, 1 p.
    re: George Sumner
  - Washington Irving to [ Daniel Lord], 1853 Feb 3; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to Sarah [Paris Storrow], 1853 Mar 28; ALS, 7 p.
  - Washington Irving to [John Pendleton] Kennedy, 1853 Sep 28; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Fred[erick] S. Cozzens, 1853 Dec 20; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to [Printers Banquet Committee], 1854 Jan 16; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Anne Irving, 1854 Mar 6; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to George P[almer] Putnam, 1854 Dec 27; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to John P[endleton] Kennedy, 1855 Apr 23; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to Library Committee of the New York Society Library, 1855 May 23; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to unknown, 1855 Jun 24; ALS, 2 p.
    with statement re:
    Life of Washington
  - Washington Irving to Stephen Taber, 1855 Sep 25; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to Alvah Beebee, 1855 Dec 7; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to Moses Thomas, 1855 Dec 14; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to Osmond Tiffany, 1855 Dec 15; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to Robert Forsyth, 1855 Dec 18; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to H. S. Smythe, 1855 Dec 26; ALS, 1 p. w/ env
  - Washington Irving to Joseph Tuttle, 1856 Feb 2; ALS, 2 p.
    in bound volume w/ Chapter 10 of
  - Washington Irving to [George] Bancroft, 1856 Feb 6; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to [Emily] Fuller, 1856 Jul 2; ALS, 6 p.
  - Washington Irving to William Thomas, 1856 Jul 31; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to [Charles C.] Lee, 1856 May 6; ALS, 3 p. w/ env
  - Washington Irving to Alfred Jones, 1857 May 10; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to W. F. Smith, 1857 May 12; ALS, 2 p.
    re: organizing a literary society
  - Washington Irving to David Appleton, 1857 May 14; ALS, 2 p.
    w/ photo of "Sunnyside" and a photo of a painting of Irving
  - Washington Irving to G[eorge] Washington Warren, 1857 May 29; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Charles C. Lee, 1857 Jul 31; ALS, 4 p. w/ env
  - Washington Irving to George Wilkes, 1857 Nov 4; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to [ Irving Association Committee], 1857 Dec 27; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to Appleton and Company, 1858 Jan 6; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to Mr. McHenry, 1858 Sep 27; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Charles Davis, 1859 Jan 12; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to Charles Davis, 1859 Feb 22; ALS, 3 p.
  - Washington Irving to R. S. Oakley, 1859 Aug 22; ALS, 1 p.
    w/ clipping and AMs copy of parts of poem, "
    Washington Irving
    " by Oakley
  - George D. Morgan to [his mother], re: death of Washington Irving, 1859 Nov 29; ALS, 1 p.
  - Pierre Irving to Charles W[arren] Stoddard, 1869 Nov 2; ALS, 2 p.
  - Marie Louise Irving to Helen, 1886 Dec 27; ALS, 4 p.
  - Washington Irving to Lady Ashburton, Jan 12; ALS, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to J. K. Mitchell, Feb 28; ALS, 1 p.
    (in third person), w/ addr
  - Washington Irving to unknown, Feb 29; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Sir Gore Ouseley, w/ addr, May 2; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Lady Brydges, May 3; AL, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to unknown, May 11; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Sir Gore [Ouseley], May 25; ALS, 1 p.
  - Sophia Hyatt to [ Thomas Wildman], Jul 13; ALS, 4 p. (transcript?)
  - Washington Irving to [ Sarah Van Wart], Sep 2; ALS, 4 p.
    (portion; may be second part of letter dated 1847 Aug 29)
  - Washington Irving to Mrs. Stuyvesant, Dec 31; AL, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to John Wetherall, w/ addr, n. d.; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to Under-Secretary of the French Embassy, AL, 2 p.
  - Washington Irving to unknown, n. d.; ANS, 1 p. (fragment)
    Voyages and Discoveries of the Companions of Columbus
  - Washington Irving to [ Thomas Aspinwall], w/ addr, n. d.; ALS, 1 p.
  - Washington Irving to [G. S.] Newton, n. d.; ALS, 2 p. (portion)
  - Washington Irving to [ Catherine Paris], w/ addr, n. d.; ALS, 1 p.
  - Antoinette Irving to William Langfeld, n. d.; ALS, 2 p.
- PHOTOGRAPHS AND PRINTS
  - Washington Irving, as a young man, seated, 1823; Engr
  - Washington Irving, as a young man, head and shoulders, 1832; Engr
  - Washington Irving, as a young man, head and shoulders (by Moseley Danforth), 1833; Engr
  - Washington Irving, as a young man, seated, (by W. Greatbatch), 1839; Engr
    w/ autograph of Washington Irving attached
  - Washington Irving, as a young man, profile (by H. B. Hall), n. d.; Engr
  - Washington Irving, as a young man, head and shoulders, Engr
  - Washington Irving, as a young man, head and shoulders, Engr
  - Washington Irving, as a young man, standing, Engr
  - Washington Irving, as a young man, head and shoulders, Engr